Henry Navarro

Software Engineer, Product & UX Designer

henrysnavarro@icloud.com | 510.378.2435 linkedin.com/in/henrynavarro github.com/henrysnavarro

Seeking senior/leadership engineering roles with special interest in machine learning, data analytics, and frontend

Versatile technology leader with 25+ years of experience and wide set of skills in software engineering, product/UX design and process management. I am a methodical problem solver, clear communicator and effective collaborator across all organizational roles. Always cognizant of product accuracy, performance and security, I am dedicated to building quality systems and continuously improving processes.

Hands-on experience in multiple verticals including manufacturing, bioinformatics, online video, e-learning, healthcare, internet-of-things, blockchain and automotive sales.

Academic backgrounds in the Physics, Computer Engineering, Business, and HCI

Skillset

Agile Scrum, Amazon Web Services, Application Security, Blockchain Architecture, CSS, Data Privacy, Data Structures and Algorithms, Design Thinking, Git, GraphQL, HTML, HTTP, Integration Testing, JavaScript, Jira, Joomla, Machine Learning Process and Algorithms, Micro-services, Mobile Applications, NPM, NodeJS, Object-oriented Programming, Open API, Rapid Prototyping, React, Relational Databases & SQL, REST, System Design, TensorFlow, TypeScript, UI Component Libraries, Unit Testing, Unix Shell Scripts, UX Design, Web Applications, and many others

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Volvo Cars Technology, Sunnyvale, CA, Nov 2020 - Present Frontend feature implementation, code delivery maintenance, code review, UX review, work planning, vendor liaison, mentoring

Senior Design Technologist, Edelman Financial Engines, Santa Clara, CA – Jul 2019 - Present Architect/Staff-Level Engineer/Designer performing lead roles in UI design and development, systems design and process optimization. Built from the ground up multiple product websites. Led team of offshore engineers, providing mentoring and process improvement. Implements robust user interfaces for financial transactions

Senior UI Engineer, BlockRules, Fremont, CA - Oct 2018 - March 2019

Frontend UI design and development of digital currency account setup and trading. Created operations monitoring dashboards for blockchain transactions.

Senior UX Design Technologist, GE Digital: San Ramon, CA - Nov 2015 - May 2018

UI Engineer and Designer. Implemented re-usable UI components and developed web application starter kits that accelerate product prototyping. Designed interactive visual diagrams that illustrate product vision. Mentored and trained engineers for adoption of our products.

Senior Software Engineer, GE Healthcare - Aug 2014 - Oct 2015

Frontend UI design and development in eHealthcare platform. Implemented UI security layer that became standard for entire platform.

Senior Software Engineer, ABB Solar Group: San Jose, CA — Jul 2012 - Jul 2014

Frontend UI design and development in Renewable Energy Monitoring solutions. Enhanced monitoring web applications for solar panels. Created interactive prototypes for envisioned next-generation products

(Comprehensive work experience available upon request)

Education

Product Management Certificate, Product School — May 2020
Certified Product Owner and Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance — May 2016
Essential Leadership Skills, GE Leadership Program — Jun 2015
Graduate Certificate in HCI, Iowa State University — Dec 2012
MBA Units, California State University East Bay —Dec 2005
Certificate in Computer Networks, UC Santa Cruz Extension — May 1999
Bachelors in Physics and Computer Engineering, Ateneo de Manila — Mar 1992

(Currently attending courses in Machine Learning, Data Science and Design)